CHAITANYA UTTARWAR

Waterloo, ON | (H) 5483336319 | chaitanyauttarwar046@gmail.com

Professional Summary

Seasoned Java and database developer with more than 3 years of experience in fast-paced agile development. Excellent Programming and research skills. Track record of achieving exceptional results in consuming RESTful services Database services and Automation.

Technical Skills

- Programming Languages: Java, C, C++, JavaScript,
 CSS, HTML, PHP, React, Node
 - Technology: Spring Framework, Maven,
 Dialogflow, UiPath, Automation Anywhere, Katalon,
 PowerBi
- Databases: MySQL, MongoDB, SQLite, Microsoft Azure
- **Tools:** Git, Jenkins, Jira, Postman, SoapUI, Latex

Experience

Full Stack Developer 01/2020 to Present

Manulife Financials – Waterloo, ON, Canada

- Designed and Modified critical stored procedures responsible for loading employee data into the database weekly. This ensured the weekly process takes less than half time to be completed.
- Was a main contributor in running the Manulife Pulse check system which enables the leadership and peers to provide feedback for their colleagues.
- Designed and developed multiple features for various Internal apps in react and made sure it merges well with main app without affecting its latency.
- Coded and tested multiple database APIs to be consumed by the applications hosted on Pivotal cloud foundry.
- Worked extensively on Katalon scripts to ensure the automation to send and collect feedback for the pulse check is done smoothly and quickly.
- Redesigned, Modified and made new tables to accommodate the database scaling.
- Worked on various triggers to ensure the data integrity between tables is maintained. This not only took down manual work but also made sure the data between tables is well updated and error free.
- Maintained the repository with standard version controlling methods and taught the same to the team.
- Completely automated an internal process using Katalon scripts which now needs minimal human intervention.
- Created a node app and hosted on pivotal cloud foundry which consumes OData feed and populates the database. Used Cron jobs to schedule the same.
- Used React to add and improve current features of an internal app. Consumed various services using Manulife, Microsoft and Survey monkey APIs.

Programmer Analyst 09/2017 to 04/2019

Cognizant Technology Solutions Pvt Ltd - Chennai, TN, India

• Contributed to spring framework build in Maven and Jenkins to develop RESTful web services which were to be used by America's leading Investor-owned utility.

- Conducted logical analysis of engineering, and other technical problems. Formulated models of solutions.
- Contributed, deployed and maintained various webservices on Heroku as well as EC2/AWS.
- Developed and tested a chatbot for client website on Dialogflow with webhooks running on google firebase.
- Worked on a chatbot for Facebook messenger with webhooks coded in php and running on Heroku.
- Created an automation tool for internal process on UiPath and Automation Anywhere.
- Achieved a global rank of 12 in an internal competition on Java and was given a title of "Orbit Shifter"

Education

Graduate Certificate, Mobile Solutions Development:

May 2019 – August 2020

Conestoga College - Waterloo, Ontario

- Coursework related to HTML, React, CSS, JavaScript, Android, iOS and C#
- Scored 3.89 GPA
- Made it to the Dean's honor's list with no subject less than 80%

Bachelor of Engineering, Computer Science:

August 2012 - May 2017

Pune University - Pune, Maharashtra

• Graduated in top 5% of the class. (GPA: 3.9/4.0, First Class with High Distinction)